HIROKO BOUZAS

UX/UI Designer, Web Developer

UX/UI design professional with +10 years of experiences from full stack designer in IT startups to lead UX designer in a leading company.

I bring creative problem-solving approach and engineering logical perspective together to create simple but elegant products.

My overseas work experience has provided me deep empathy over culture differences, which fuels my passion to craft inclusive and intuitive experience for people.

Experience

Chief UX Designer 2018 - Present

U-NEXT.Co.,Ltd. / Tokyo Japan

- Lead product design team to provide intuitive and coherent user experience of complexed cross platformed application.
- · Manage team tasks, support team members.
- · Lead Design System Project, collaborating with stakeholders and engineers.
- Plan and conduct User researches, tests, interviews with UX researchers, provide the best solutions according to the results.

Freelance Designer, Web Developer 2014 - Present

- · Design consultation, branding for small businesses, startups.
- · Project management, Art direction, scheduling, budget adjustment.
- · UX/UI design for digital products, Graphic design, Illustration.

Chief Designer 2016 - 2018

Zweispace Japan / Tokyo Japan

- Responsible for all the design materials of the company, supervised design consistency across products.
- Comprehensive design work from defining user stories to final products, considering usability and development efficiency.
- Front-end web development.
- Managing SEO for web based products, web advertisements such as Google AdWords, Facebook Ads, affiliate marketing.

Chief Designer, Front-end Developer 2015 - 2016

Nex-pro / Tokyo Japan, Yangon Myanmar

- · Responsible for all the design materials of the company.
- Educated design fundamental to Yangon's front-end development/design team through projects, managed and supervised them both in Yangon and Tokyo.
- · Front-end web development.
- Involved in web marketing projects using LP and web advertisements such as Google AdWords, Facebook Ads, affiliate marketing.

Graphic Designer, UX/UI Designer 2013 - 2014

Studio SPEC / Sydney Australia

- DTP design to transform complex information in simple way.
- · Teaching small class of graphic design foundation course.
- UX/UI design for website, web application.

Graphic Designer 2008 - 2012

UCHINO Life Style Designing / Tokyo Japan

- Delivering graphic design, product design, package design for big named brands such as Walt Disney Japan.
- · Learned principal idea of working as a team.



s+)

(+81) 70 4415 4956

http://hiroko.design/

Language

Japanese Native English Fluent

French Conversational

Work Condition

Eligible to work within European Union

Skills

User Research, Experience strategy, Information Architecture, Wire-framing, Interface Design, Responsive Web Design, Graphic Design, Design Consultation, SEO Management, Web Marketing, HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, GitHub

Education

First Certificate in English (FCE)

Cambridge Examination / Sydney Australia 2013

Bachelor of Arts /

Visual Communication Design

Musashino Art University Tokyo Japan 2004-2008